"POWER"
（ディソナス）ハハハハハハ！
This is...the Saezuri...
コイツが　ここに
長年　眠っていた　さえずり。
that has slumbered here
for many years.
古代の遺産だ。
It is a legacy from ages past!
I wasn't expecting such resistance
from the guards,
思いのほか
防人どもの抵抗が厳しくて→
so obtaining it wasn't easy...
手に入れるのに苦労したがな。
（ドック）じゃあ…。
Then...
The village head should've
minded his own business.
村長め　余計なことをしよって。
音を揃えるのに
ムダな時間を食っちまった。
I wasted precious time
in gathering the "sounds."
じゃあ　村を襲ったのは…。
Then the one
who attacked the village...
俺だ。　俺が　コイツにやらせた。
That was me.
I put him up to it.
キサマ！
Why you—!
俺が　失った力を取り戻すために→
Do you know what
I went through
どんだけ苦労したことか。
in order to regain
the power I lost...?
ここの伝承にたどり着いて
町長にまでなって→
After learning about the legend,
I went as far as
隠された秘密を　ほじくり出して→
becoming the head of
the village to dig around...
そして　確信を得たんだ。
and uncover the hidden secret.
さあ　どこだ？　残りの音は。
So, where are
the remaining "sounds"?
いたぶってる時間も惜しいんだ。
I don't have time to waste.
言えば　楽に死なせてやるぞ。
If you tell me,
I will let you die painlessly.
いや　もう殺して
穢土転生で　しゃべらせるか。
Or maybe,
I should kill you and
ハハハハハハハハッ！
make you talk with
the Reanimation.
（ナルト）テメエ！
いやぁ…　ナルト君。
Why you—!
すごいな　キミは。
And you, Naruto.
You're amazing!
あの暁のペインを
倒したそうじゃないか。
I hear you brought down Pain
of the Akatsuki.
この私でさえ
敗れたというのに。
そのせいで　力を失ったが
それでも…。
Even someone like me
couldn't beat him.
テメエの過去なんざ　どうでもいい！
That's how I lost my power.
おっちゃんに手を出したら→
— But I lived...
— I could care less about your past!
ぶっ殺すぞ！
If you lay a hand on him,
I'll kill you!
ぐわっ！
Those snakes...consume chakra...
（カブト）その蛇たちは　チャクラを食らう。
The more you increase your chakra,
the tighter they squeeze.
キミが　チャクラを高めれば高めるほど→
拘束が強くなるのさ。
クソが　偉そうに！
You bastard!
You're so full of yourself.
Just who do you think you are?
何様のつもりだ！
（ソラ）キャッ！
（レオ）こ　これ…。
H-Here!
これだろ？
お前らの欲しがってるやつ。
This is what you want, right?
やるから
ドック先生とナルト兄ちゃんを返せ！
You can have it,
so let Dokku Sensei and Naruto go!
どうやら　音は
子供たちが持っていたようだね。
It seems these kids
had the "sounds."
なに？
What?!
上に来ている。
They're up above.
健気に　アンタを
助けに来たみたいだ。
It seems they're so brave,
they've come to save you.
（ネジ）カブト…　おそらく分身と→
Kabuto...
He's likely a clone...
and about five children.
たぶん　子供が５人。
（シセル）あの子たち！
家にいないと思ったら　なんで？
The kids! I wondered
where they went... Why?
（カカシ）とにかく
慎重に近づきましょう。
In any case,
let's approach cautiously.
always chasing after your shadow
itsu made mo oikakete iru anata no zanzo wo
when you dream, your face looks like it did before
yume ni miru yokogao ha ano koro no mama de
you run into the tall grass and disappear
se no takai kusanami ni hashiri satte kieta
I push through the memories and follow you
omoidasu kioku wo kakewake atoo uboku ha
it's frustrating as I run out of breath and in the end I'm unable to reach you
modokashiku mo iki wo kirashite saigo ha todokazu ni
far away
tooku
how many years ago was it?
nannenmae no koto desho
I left my heart at that place
nidoto modorenai ano basho ni
where I can never return
oite kite shimatta boku no kokoro sa
if this is a dream, if I can't get it back
moshimo yume naraba tori modosenai no nara
then how can I tell you how I feel?
kono kimochi ha do shite utaereba ii no
I'm still chasing after the shadow from that day
imadani oikakete iru ano hi no zanzo wo
though I spend my days in sorrow
kanashimi ni ake kurenagara mo ima
I'll live on in this world without you
anata naki sekai de boku wa ikiru yo
（みんな）あっ　先生！
— Sensei!
みんな！
Everyone!
フフフフフ。
やめろ！
子供たちに手を出すな！
Stop!
Don't lay a hand on the children!
フッ。
揃った…。
I got them all!
揃ったぞ　７本　すべて。
I got all seven of them!
やった～　やったぞ！
I did it! I actually did it!
これで　力を取り戻せる。
Now my "power" will return!
アハハハハハハハ！
《どうすれば…》
How can I...
《チャクラを食らう？》
Consume...chakra?
力の制御には　７本の音を
組み合わせたパターンを利用して→
One takes control of
the "power" by activating it
規定の手順にのっとり
起動させる。
with a combination of
seven "sounds."
力の放出量は　パターンの変化により
増減させることができる。
By varying the sound patterns,
you can increase and
decrease the level of "power."
音を利用した入力は
手動操作による更新→
Inputting this sound can
be a manual operation...
もしくは　七つ時ごとに
自動で感知　更新される。
Or it will automatically renew
its power every 12 hours.
音の組み合わせが
パターンにない不当な場合は→
If a certain sound pattern does
not exist and is not recognized,
前回の更新内容が維持される。
the previous pattern
will be maintained.
これが正しければ…。
If this is correct...
ああ！
Mina!
あっ！　ミィナ！
う…。
How could you be so reckless?!
なんで　こんなムチャを！
Because...
We wanted...
だって…。
先生に…。
...to see you, Sensei
（ファズ）先生に会いたいもん！
アハハハハハ！
Amazing... amazing...
This is amazing!
すげえ…　すげえ　すげえぞ！
This is impressive...
驚いたな。
これが　天の矛？
This is...the "Ama no Hoko"?
これが起動のパターンなら
力の解放は…。
If this is the activation pattern,
the way to release "power" is...!
（カカシ）
過ぎた野心は　身を滅ぼす。
Too much ambition... is destructive.
これは　もう
人の扱う代物じゃない。
This is no longer something
people should use.
昔の手配書リストも確認したよ。
I verified it on an old bulletin
of wanted persons...
暁と争って
死んだと思われていたようだな。
Apparently,
it was believed you died
in a scuffle with the Akatsuki.
口寄せ術を得意とし→
You specialized in
the Summoning Jutsu,
殺めた人の数は
数千ともいわれた　殺人狂。
and you were known
as a homicidal maniac
who claimed
several thousand victims.
禁術の穢土転生を
大蛇丸とともに研究していた。
Along with Orochimaru,
you researched the forbidden
Reanimation Jutsu...
フフッ。
観念しろ　ディソナス！
Give up, Disonasu!
お兄ちゃん！
シセル！
Brother!
Shiseru?
（飛段）テメエは！
You're.
ソイツは　俺がやる。
That guy is mine!
ナルト君！
（サクラ）ナルト！
（ヒナタ）ナルト君！
Naruto!
Naruto...
ゴホゴホ！
（デイダラ）フフッ。
うん！
ハハハハ！
It's all over for you guys!
テメエら　これで終わりだ！
いの！　チョウジ！
Inc! Choji!
あっ！
（サイ）サクラ！
Sakura!
芸術を味わえ！
Get a little taste of some art!
芸術は爆発だ！
Art is...
an explosion!
《シカマル：ヤツが儀式を行うには
呪印を描かなきゃならねえ。
He needs to create a Curse Mark
in order to perform the ritual.
その隙を与えなきゃいいんだ》
So we can't give him
a chance to do so...
まさか…。
No way...
うわぁ～！
ぐっ…　ハァ　ハァ　ハァ。
なんだ　お前は…。
What are you...?
お前の　その力！
This power of yours...
俺は　今まで
いろんな大切なことを→
いろんな人に教わってきた。
Over the years, I've been taught
a lot of important things
今さっきだって
すげぇ　強い人に→
from a lot of people...
大切なことを教わったんだ。
Even now, I learned something
from an incredibly strong person.
俺の力は→
螺旋丸や仙術や
九尾のチャクラなんかじゃねえ！
My "power" isn't the Rasengan
or Sage Jutsu...
俺の力は…。
or the Nine Tails' chakra.
My power is...
ここだ！
right here!
サイ！
Sail
穢土転生の忍が復活しないだと？
A reanimated shinobi
that doesn't resurrect?
（ガイ）どうやら
捨て駒にしたようだな。
I guess...
they were sacrificial pawns.
やっと捕らえたぜ！
We finally got you!
テメエ！
Why you—!
アンタの能力は
サポートがなけりゃ生かせねえ。
Your ability is useless without
back-up support.
長ったらしい段取りのせいでな。
It's because it requires
$0 many steps.
サポートか…　なら。
Support, huh? Well then...
ったく　世話の焼けるダンナだぜ！
Damn, he's such a nuisance!
これで…。
Now then!
（ヤマト）これ以上は　させないよ。
That's as far as you'll go.
こんな…　とこで！
諦めろ。
As if...
I'm gonna...
こんなとこで
諦めてたまるか！
Give it up.
Like I'm gonna give up
at this point!
あん！？
This is...!
これは！
Hey! What the hell...?
Damn you!
おい　何だよ　テメエ！
どうやら　お前の元になってる
クローン蛇ってのには→
Looks like that clone snake
that constitutes you
大きな欠陥があるみてえだな。
has a big defect...
急速に成長する分
寿命も短いってとこか。
They reach maturity quickly,
but their lifespan
is just as short.
That about explains it.
念のため　あと二十手ほどの対策を
考えていたが→
Just in case, I came up
with 20 more strategies...
必要なかったみてぇだな。
I guess that wasn't necessary.
（みんな）うわぁ～！
何？　今の…。
What was that just now?!
崩れ落ちている。
The ground caved in...
ここの地面は→
This terrain was raised up
and supported by tree roots...
木の根に支えられて
浮いている状態なんだ。
早く　ホールから逃げないと。
え？　うん。
We have to get away from
the "Hole" immediately!
Y-Yeah.
（ミィナ）先生　あれは止まらないの？
Sensei!
Is that thing going to stop?
世界を覆いし　その力は
世界を滅ぼす。
Power will cloak the world...
and destroy it...
力…。
あの力を浴びれば…。
"Power..."
ヘヘッ。
If I bathe in that "power"...
I wonder why I can't fly
nande kanaa sora ga tobenai no wa
even though in my dreams, I have wings
yume no naka no boku wa hane ga haeten no ni
I'm going to surpass my limits and leave this place
genkai wo koete tobidasou koko kara
I'll drive away my loneliness with you
samishisa fuki tobasu kimi to kimi to
"I love you" and "good bye" have disappeared
i love you mo sayonara mo ienakatta
leaving me here incomplete
koko ni fukanzen na boku dake wo nokoshite
you still haven't taught me the song of love
ai no uta kimi ni mada tsutaetenai yo
of this dazzling world
dokomademo mabushiku kagayaku sekai wo
of this song
kono uta wo
Next Episode
That's why
I'll never let go again!
＜旬の魚が大好きな豆助＞
If I do, we'll fall together!
I've been in love with you
since then!
豆助　きょうのお魚は
今が旬のアレよ
But who's going to protect
the children!
You're the only one!
You're the only one
who can save their future!
＜　その魚とは…＞
But... But!
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
＜　それは幼いころ→
"Power — Episode Final"
群れるさまが
花に似ていることから→
Next Episode
Please. Save us.